(+20) 1153383255 sofyan1020@gmail.com Resides in Egypt

Sofyan Mahmoud

Software engineer

LinkedIn Leetcode Github

PROFILE

Passionate software engineer with **over two years of experience**. I graduated from the **Faculty of Engineering**, Computer Department at **Cairo University** in Egypt. My primary interest lies in web development, particularly in backend. I have gained extensive experience through my involvement in various projects, using different frameworks and languages including **Flask/Python**, **Spring Boot/Java**, **Laravel/PHP**, **Node.js**, **React.js**, **and C++**. Additionally, I have worked with diverse database engines such as **MySQL**, **PostgreSQL**, **and MongoDB**. Furthermore, I am deeply passionate about **problem-solving**, and I am proud to have recently achieved a **top 5% ranking in the LeetCode community** for my problem-solving skills.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering, Software Engineering, Cairo university, Grade: Very Good

2016 - 2021

- Overall Grade: Very Good, GP grade: Excellent
- Graduation project: A software solution called Autoeye is used to help the autonomous vehicle in adverse weather conditions, solution pipeline was dedicated in detection of the current state of the environment surrounding the vehicle and then apply computer vision and deep learning techniques to enhance the vision stream from the camera in order to be used to make the actions better

EXPERIENCE

Back-end engineer @ Settle

Egypt | 2023.09 — Present

- Working on a **Microservices** project to automate the process of b2b pay- ments enabling clients to pay all their suppliers in a seamless few clicks.
- Stack: Flask/Python, Postgresql, RabbitMQ

C++ instructor @ MEC Academy

Egypt | 2023.08 — 2023.12

- Teaching programming fundamentals, OOP, Data structure and algorithms using C++ languages
- I've taught two groups, each includes about 15 students

Back-end engineer @ Eden technologies

Egypt | 2022.12 — 2023.09.

- Working on Microservices for car parking management system used in smart villages in Saudi Arabia.
- Stack: Java/Spring-boot, Flask/Python, Postgresql, MongoDB, RabbitMQ

Front-end engineer @ Egyptian armed forces

Egypt | 2021.11 — 2022.12.

- · Working on ERP system used in Egyptian armed forces.
- · Stack: React, Java script

Full-stack engineer @ NajahNow

Egypt | 2020.06 — 2021.03.

- Working on Online educational platform used for education during COVID- 19 pandemic.
- Stack: PHP/Laravel, Blade templates, JS, HTML, CSS, MySQL

SKILLS

Concepts: Algorithms, Data structure, Problem solving, OOP, OOD, Design patterns, RESTful APIs.

Tools: Git, Github, Docker. Programming Languages C++, Java, Python, php, Js.

Database: SQL, MySQL, MongoDB, PostgreSql.

Queuing system RabbitMQ.
OS Linux, Windows

Human languages English (B2), Arabic (native)

RECENT ACHIEVEMENTS

Solved +1100 problems in leetcode and reached the top 3% in the leetcode cummunity